mywindows8.org 2018-07-26

# Privacy Policy - My Windows Hub

## Who we are

Our website address is: http://mywindowshub.com.

## What personal data we collect, why we collect and where do we send it

### 1\. Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comment form, the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created for your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Apart from the default comment system, we also use [Facebook Comments Plugin](https://developers.facebook.com/products/social-plugins/comments/?utm_campaign=social_plugins&utm_medium=offsite_pages&utm_source=comments_plugin). We have discussed about it later in  **Social Media Plugins and Comment Plugins** section.

Visitors’ comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. In comment section it is only required to provide Name and Email address to post any comment (not required for Facebook comment plugin). Approved comments can be seen by all visitors. Email ID will not be published along with your comment. Mywindowshub.com will never ask for Credit Card details, telephone number, full address etc. and request you not to post any such personal details on any of the forms or in comment section.

### 2\. Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website

### 3\. Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Besides, our website uses cookies for analytics, advertisements, social sharing buttons and Facebook comment plugin. We have discussed all these in details in later sections.

### 4\. Third Party Websites

Third party Internet sites or services linked to from this website may have different privacy policies and practices. Mywindowshub.com is not responsible for any data handling and privacy practices of third party sites or areas of this website, that are operated by third parties. You should carefully review all those privacy policies in order to determine how each third party may use any personal information you provide and please contact those third parties directly if you have any questions about their privacy policies.

### 5\. Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### 6\. Analytics

Like millions of other website owners, we also use Google Analytics on mywindowshub.com. Google Analytics uses cookies that enable an analysis of visitor’s use of the website.

#### What does Google Analytics record?

Referrer URL (what website the visitor came from to get here)  
How long the visitor stay for  
Time of the visit of our website  
Visitor’s operating system, browser  
And quite a bit more.

These details are generally transmitted to and stored on a server of Google.

#### What do we do with this data?

The tracking information allows us to better understand the kind of people who come to our website and what content they are reading. This allows us to make better decisions about writing and design. Occasionally, We will compile aggregate statistics about the number of visitors this site receives, at what time visitor count is high, which pages have got the maximum number of visits, etc. No personally identifying data is included in this type of reporting. All our activities fall within the bounds of the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html).

###  **7\. Ads**

Mywindowshub.com uses Google Adsense to display advertisements on this website. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this website. These cookies allow Google’s ad servers to serve ads to mywindowshub.com visitors, based on their visit to this website and other websites on the Internet. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by mywindowshub.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertiser. In mywindowshub.com Google shows only non-personalized ads to the visitors in the EEA. Non-personalized ads are targeted using contextual information rather than the past behavior of a user. Although these ads don’t use cookies for ads personalization, they do use cookies to allow for frequency capping, aggregated ad reporting, and to combat fraud and abuse.

Users can get more details and control the use of these advertising cookies by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

###  8\. Social Media Plugins and Comment Plugins

Mywindowshub.com uses social media plugins, in particular, the Facebook Like button and comment plugin, Google Plus button, Twitter buttons on most of the web pages, which have articles/contents that visitors may want to share or comment on. When visitors visit those web pages, their browsers will directly connect to the respective Facebook, Google and/or Twitter servers and load the buttons from there. At the same time, Facebook, Google and/or Twitter will know that the respective page on our website has been visited. This is to improve visitor’s website experience and to optimize our website.

We have no influence on the data that Facebook, Google and Twitter collect on the basis of the social buttons or comment box. According to the available information, however, if a visitor does not click on these social media buttons or does not post comments in the Facebook comment box, no personal data will be collected and stored unless the visitor has logged onto to his Facebook, Google or Twitter account. In that case, certain user data (including the visitor’s IP address at that time) may be collected and linked to the account information already present at Facebook, Google or Twitter, respectively. This can be prevented if the visitor logs out of social media accounts (Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter) before visiting this website.

In addition, clicking a social share button or commenting on the Facebook comment box may also lead to a collection of certain data, such as the user’s IP address. Facebook, Google or Twitter may set cookies as well, unless you have disabled the acceptance and storage of cookies in your browser settings. When a visitor is posting a comment using Facebook Comment plugin in our website, there is an option to post the same comment on your Facebook too, in that case you need to explicitly check “Also post on Facebook” option before posting the comment on our website.  The Facebook comment plugin allows the visitor to modify/delete all of his comments (comments posted on this website using Facebook comment Plugin) any time, if he/she is already logged onto his Facebook account when visiting our website.

More information on this topic can be obtained here:

• Facebook’s Privacy Policy [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) , Additional Information on Facebook’s Social Plugins  [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#socialplugin)

• Google’s +1 Button Privacy Policy [here](https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy)

• Twitter’s Privacy Policy [here](https://twitter.com/en/privacy)

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

Currently mywindowshub.com does not have register/signup facility for the visitors/viewers. There is no requirement of signing up or creating a login account here in mywindowshub.com to read the published contents on mywindowshub.com.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Contact US

Please check our [Contact us](http://mywindowshub.com/contact-us/) page for any details.
